<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tiago dos Santos</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tiago dos Santos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>santos.tmd@gmail.com (Tiago dos Santos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>santos.tmd@gmail.com (Tiago dos Santos)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 12:25:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of Infected Individuals by COVID-19 in Portugal using the SEIR Model</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-14-covid19simulationsseir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 12:25:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>santos.tmd@gmail.com (Tiago dos Santos)</author>
      <guid>/post/2020-03-14-covid19simulationsseir/</guid>
      <description>Simulating some COVID-19 scenarios in Portugal with the SEIR Model While on reddit, I came across this paper called “Phase-adjusted estimation of the number of Coronavirus Disease 2019 cases in Wuhan, China”, where the authors applied a model to rum some simulations and reason about if the public health interventions indeed suffice or not.
In the paper, the model used is the SEIR Model - that I had never heard about until today (well, I started this by 9PM on 2020-03-13, and now it is 2AM 2020-03-14)… Until I gave it a try, some googling and youtubing until I understand it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting (more) confortable with statistics</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-18-statscourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>santos.tmd@gmail.com (Tiago dos Santos)</author>
      <guid>/post/2018-11-18-statscourse/</guid>
      <description>During this summer, I’ve taken the decision of getting better at Statistics. My relationship with statistics was a kind of relation that I coukd stare at it and maybe get an intuition of what’s going on, but no more than that. Anything that involved, for example, understanding how is a Pearson’ correlation matrix calculated and what’s the meaning of the math behind that gave me the chills since I really had bad foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing a new challenge: Feedzai!</title>
      <link>/post/2017-12-03-feedzai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>santos.tmd@gmail.com (Tiago dos Santos)</author>
      <guid>/post/2017-12-03-feedzai/</guid>
      <description>Since 2016 I’ve been focusing on data science and distributed computing, a path that I’ve decided to take back in late 2014 when I got back do University to take a Masters in Computer Science. At the time, I was looking to learn a bit about machine learning and tons about distributed system and web development - but while I was learning more about Operational Research and Machine Learning, my direction changed a little bit and I begin to study Data Visualization and Data Warehouse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>